## TOMISLAV SOKAC

APP 1 Block 3D Belgrade Square West, Tallaght, Dublin 24, Ireland tsokac2@gmail.com • 085 819 68 18

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tomislav-sokac2

GitHub: https://github.com/tsokac2

#### SUMMARY

Meticulous Junior Front End Developer having 3 years' experience in developing personal user Interface applications and professional web applications using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript (Es5 and ES6), jQuery, and Bootstrap.

Recent Code Institute diploma in software development recipient including Microsoft Azure AZ-900 certification and progressing towards Azure DevOps solutions expert.

Strong knowledge of Python and Django framework, highly experienced in code debugging through research, testing, discovery Reddit, Stack Overflow, MDN Web Docs.

A strong communicator, organized, can read between the lines to understand business needs and prioritize work accordingly in high-pressure environments.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **SUPPORT**

Applications Active Directory, Lansweeper, Veeam B&R, SAP, CMD, RDP, Server Manager, SCCM, PowerShell

Network Freshservice Helpdesk, Teams, TeamViewer, Slack, Zoom, Cisco AnyConnect, Webex

Cloud OKTA, O365 Admin Console, VMware, Azure, Sophos, Symantec Cyber Security, MobileIron Go, Adobe Admin

OS Windows 11, Windows 10, iOS, Android, Windows Server 2012, Windows Server 2019

#### **DEVELOPMENT**

Applications Balsamiq, Photoshop, Illustrator, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Atom

Network GitHub/Git, WinSCP, FileZilla, JIRA

LanguagesHTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Python, SQLFrameworksDjango, Flask, Bootstrap, Jasmine, Angular JSCloudAWS S3, Azure, MongoDB, Stripe, Heroku, JIRA

Methods Object-Oriented Programming, Performance Testing, Load Testing & Debugging, Responsive Design & Mobile-

First Websites, API Implementation, Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# **IT Operation Support Specialist**

Exertis Global Operations, Ireland <u>exertisglobaloperations.com</u> Jan 2020 - Present

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

**REPORTING** - Control incremental, weekly, and monthly backups with Veeam Backup & Replication software.

- Monitoring health, applications, connectivity, and security for users IT assets via Lansweeper application.

- Update and maintain detailed external and internal IT documentation.

**SECURITY** - Symantec Endpoint enrolment with redistributable installation package for Windows and Mac devices.

- Sophos enrolment with redistributable installation package for Windows devices.

- Importing and creating default or custom security policies.

**USER SUPPORT** - Assist with new hire onboarding and training curriculum.

Walk users through problem-solving processes.Respond to queries via email, MS Teams, or Freshservice ticketing system.

- Supervise users for MFA configurations with personal or company mobile devices via OKTA Verify app.

SaaS - O365 Admin licensing control, SharePoint orchestration, Teams channels collections management.

- Generate DL lists, shared emails delegations, groups, user mailboxes with the Exchange admin center.

- MobileIron Android and iOS mobile device security container configuration and control.

- vSphere - VM's control and monitoring - Disaster recovery testing.

**PROJECTS** - Troubleshoot IT scripts, systems, or automation.

- SAP transports requests deployments with the JIRA tracking process.

- Supervising weekly e-commerce store deployments for testing, staging, and production cycles.

# **Desktop Support Engineer**

BNP Paribas, Ireland <u>bnpparibas.ie/en/</u> Apr 2019 – Jan 2020

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

**REPORTING** - Stand-up session review and planning for Windows 10 migration project target 600+ users.

- Daily migration targets according to available resources including HVD and HP G5 EliteBook.

- Monitoring Windows 10 pre-build Imaging process and reporting accordingly.

- Remote collaboration with central IT operation office regarding new system updates.

**USER SUPPORT** - Operational efficiencies by streamlining and automating routine work tasks in conjunction with ServiceNow.

Application updates, licenses, and subscription configurations for Adobe Creative Cloud.
Remote support via Goverlan Reach Console after successful Windows 10 migration.

SaaS - SCCM packages installation against SDG user-profile including SAP, Adobe Creative Cloud.

- O365 implementation of advanced Excel macros configuration via CMD interface.

**PROJECTS** - New workstations build scope control and MAC address implementation and configuration.

- Supervising and managing user HVD profiles migration from Windows 7 to Windows 10.

- Application migration respectfully from Windows 7 to Windows 10.

- Configuring Bloomberg workstation according to company standards and regulatory compliance.

# **Merchandising Assistant**

LEMAP Ltd – Innovators in Fashion diesel.ie/ Nov 2016 – Apr 2019

# **Team Lead - Department of Activities**

**Udemy Certificate** 

Melia Hotels International melia.com Jun 2010 – Oct 2016

## **WEB PROJECTS**

STUDY	New Irish Life	Django, JS SASS, AWS S3, Stripe, Google API	newirishlife.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
	NewIrishLife-3-0	Python, JS, SASS, Google API, Email JS, MongoDB	new-irish-life-3-0.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
	NewIrishLife-2-0	jQuery, JS, SASS, Google API, Email JS	tsokac2.github.io/newlrishLife.2.0/	GitRepo

NexterSASS, jQuery, CSS Grid, Flexboxres-nexter.herokuapp.com/NatoursSASS, jQuery, CSSres-natours.herokuapp.com/"Georgia"SASS, jQuery, CSSres-georgia.herokuapp.com/

PUBLIC New Ireland Life JavaScript, CSS newirelandlife.com

Resume Angular JS, SASS tomislavsokac.com

Showreel TsR JavaScript, CSS tomislavsokac.com/showreel.html

## **EDUCATION**

FINISHED	Microsoft Certification	H939-1488	AZ-900 Azure fundamentals	Aug 2021
	Code Institute	SB2008FS	Diploma in Software Development	Aug 2021
	Udemy Certificate	UC-0R8PP9DZ	Advance CSS - CSS Grid - Flexbox	Oct 2019
	Udemy Certificate	UC-GD4CICQ8	SASS (CSS Pre-processor)	Apr 2019
	Udemy Certificate	UC-75UYCA3	Full Stack Developer	Mar 2019
	Udemy Certificate	UC-CGHKHNRP	Windows Server 2019 – Windows 10 Pro	Sep 2019
	University of Zagreb, Croatia		Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (B.C.S.)	Dec 2009
PREPARATION	ION Microsoft Certification		AZ-204 Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure	Aug 2021
	Udemy Certificate		React & Django Full Stack	Aug 2021
PLANED	Microsoft Certification		AZ-400 Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions	Oct 2021

React - The Complete Guide

Oct 2021